Wilton Historical Society Manuscript Collection
Wilton History Room, Wilton Historical Society
- David Hermon Van Hoosear papers
  - Church - Congregational in Redding - Baptisms, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1102)
  - Church - Congregational in Stratford - Index and records of of baptisms and marriages, 1747-1786; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. Records cover January 1747 to July 1786. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1114)
  - Church - Darien - Records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1058)
  - Church - Fairfield - Index to records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1066)
  - Church - Greenfield in Fairfield - Records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1064)
  - Church - Greens Farms in Westport - Miscellaneous notes and index to records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1124)
  - Church - Norfield in Weston - Baptisms, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1120)
  - Church - Norfield in Weston - Parish petition, 1756; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1123)
  - Church - Norfield in Weston - Records, 1757-1878; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1122)
  - Church - Presbyterian in South Salem, New York - Records and index, 1752; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1108)
  - Church - Ridgebury - Records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1104)
  - Church - Wilton Congregational - Baptisms, 1731-1887; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1140)
  - Colchester - Miscellaneous records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1056)
  - Fairfield - Woodbury probate records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1132)
  - Fairfield early vital statistics - Index, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1068)
  - Fairfield probate records - Index, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1070)
  - Fairfield Vital Statistics - Family book, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1062)
  - Fancher, "Squire" - Marriages recorded at Pound Ridge, New York, 1838-1871; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1100)
  - Gregory, John of Cranbury, Norwalk - Account book names, 1795-1808; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1084)
  - Hall's Norwalk - Corrections, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1085a)
  - Hall's Norwalk - Index, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1085b)
  - Livestock - Ear marks, undated; Includes drawings of ear marks and a notebook detailing ear marks registered for cattle in Fairfield during the years 1712-1770. David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1053)
  - Miscellaneous principal public records - Index, 1903; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1072)
  - New Canaan deaths and vital statistics - Index, 1773; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. Records date from January 1, 1773. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1076)
  - New Haven - Churchman's Monthly, 1804; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1080)
  - Norwalk property records - Index to volumes 1-12, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1088, 1090)
  - Ridgefield - Vital statistics, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1106)
  - Stamford - Baptisms and marriages, 1747; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1112)
  - Van Hoosear, David Hermon - Correspondence, papers, and property records, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1052)
  - Van Hoosear, David Hermon - Literary works, undated; Includes an index of his Norwalk Hour columns. See Notebooks #47a - #47e for original columns. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1051b)
  - Van Hoosear, David Hermon - Summary list of manuscripts and genealogical materials, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1051a)
  - Wallingford and Cheshire - Vital statistics and church records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1116)
  - War - Revolutionary - List of Tories from Norwalk, 1780; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1092)
  - Weston - Early vital statistics from property records, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1118)
  - Windham - List of deaths, undated; Contains David Hermon Van Hoosear's notes on vital records from a locality near Wilton. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1130)
- G. Evans Hubbard papers
  - Book Barn, 1945-1947 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 460)
  - Certificates, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 461)
  - Correspondence, 1939-1943; Includes correspondence regarding Dr. F. Ward Denys's portrait, and correspondence from late in life. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 462a, 462b)
  - Credit Union, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 463)
  - Houses for veterans, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 465b)
  - Hubbard, G. Evans - Miscellaneous papers, 1812-1814 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 464a)
  - Minor court - Complaints and commitments, 1939-1941 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 422)
  - Minor court - Motor vehicles, 1939-1940; Includes correspondence. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 426, 428)
  - Minor court - Penalties, 1941 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 430)
  - Minor court - Probation, 1939 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 432)
  - Minor court - Reports, 1939-1940 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 434)
  - Minor court - System, 1938-1939 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 424)
  - Minor court cases, 1939-1940 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 421)
  - Norwalk, Ohio, 1935 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 464b)
  - Papers, undated; See also WHI, Personalities (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 420)
  - Personal papers, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 466a)
  - Property records, 1926-1946; Includes information on house rental and purchase of property on Ridgefield Road. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 465a, 466b)
  - Wilton courts, 1925-1939 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 438, 440, 442)
  - Wilton courts - Assembly of trial justices, 1930-1940 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 444, 446)
  - Wilton courts - Correspondence, 1940-1943 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 448, 450)
  - Wilton Justice Court, 1939-1940 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 436)
- 4. Miscellaneous
  - Town of Wilton - Selectmen’s meetings, resolutions, and votes, 1861-1863 (Box OS-1006, Folder *)
  - Anonymous - A Wilton tailor's financial records, 1783-1806; Includes copies of an account book. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 90)
  - Anonymous - Literary works, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 540)
  - Apprenticeships, 1792-1868; James Bull to Jonathon Middlebrook; Julia Hower to M. Hower and M. John. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 118)
  - Cannon Men's Chorus, undated; See also WHI, Printed Matter. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 227)
  - Cemetery - Bald Hill Cemetery, 1895 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 238)
  - Cemetery - St. Matthews, 1886-1960; Includes a burial ground plan and notes by custodian Frank Rockwell. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 230)
  - Church - Episcopal Society, 1812 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 299a)
  - Church - St. Matthew's Episcopal - Episcopal Missionary Society of Wilton, 1822-1833 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 790)
  - Church - St. Matthew's Episcopal - Sabbath School directors, 1842-1848; Includes information on or by Helen Gregory. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 791)
  - Church - Sunday School Society, 1828-1835 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 272)
  - Church - Wilton Congregational - History, undated; See also Ledgers 101-107, Parish Records. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 271aa)
  - Church - Wilton Congregational - Ladies Home Missionary Society, 1835-1860; See also WHI, Church, and WHI, Printed Matter. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 271b)
  - Church - Wilton Congregational - Second Meeting House, 1737-1740; Includes Building Progress Reports for the Second Meeting House. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 271a)
  - Church - Zion's Hill Methodist - Bequest, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1358)
  - Church - Zion's Hill Methodist - Cemetery and burial records, 1897-1911 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1360)
  - Church - Zion's Hill Methodist - Repairs, 1840; Includes information on the Church Repair and Improvement Fund, and a List of Paid Subscribers (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1362)
  - French and Indian War - Wilton train band (militia), 1710-1717 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1047)
  - Gregory Brothers Auto Repair - Financial and executive records, 1932-1944; Includes invoices and a patent. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 358b)
  - Gregory Saw Mill, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 375)
  - Indentures, 1837-1838; Includes indentures of James Vance to J.P. Fitch, and James Vance to Joseph P. and Henry Wickham and Samuel Hutchenson. (Box Cabinet: 24, Folder MC 7-2)
  - Insurance policies, 1875-1901; Seth Grumman, and Sylvester and Betsy Ann Grumman, and First School District (Box Cabinet: 24, Folder MC 7-3)
  - Livestock, farming, and forestry, 1852-1864; Includes information on sheep. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 101)
  - Medicine and medicinal recipes, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 580)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 650)
  - Nichols & Cole Carriage Makers, 1856-1877 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 660)
  - Promissory notes, 1824-1870 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 759)
  - Railroad - Correspondence and financial records, 1863-1887; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 762)
  - Railroad - Station subscription, 1851 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 760)
  - Republican Town Committee, 1937; Includes the Treasurer's lists. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 775a)
  - Republican Town Committee - Elijah Reed, undated; See also MAN 161. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 775b)
  - Schools - Belden Hill - Financial records, 1839-1899; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 164)
  - Schools - Correspondence, 1893 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 298b)
  - Schools - Designation of School Districts, 1891 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 298c)
  - Schools - Elmer Eliakim, 1753 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 298e)
  - Schools - Gilbert and Bennett, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 346)
  - Schools - Hurlbutt Street School District, 1840-1850; See also Hurlbutt Street School House Records, in Register. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 485a)
  - Schools - Nod Hill - Financial records, 1875-1924; Includes receipts and papers. See also MC. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 665)
  - Schools - School District no. 10, 1852; Contains copies. (Box Cabinet: 24, Folder MC 7-9)
  - Schools - School District no. 2, undated-1880; Includes school registers. (Box Cabinet: 24, Folder MC 7-11)
  - Schools - School District no. 4, 1816; Includes information on Dolly Gregory, a teacher. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 799a)
  - Schools - School Districts - Property records, 1910; Information on leasing. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 298d)
  - Schools - School Society - Financial records, 19th century; See also MAN, Nod Hill School. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 799b)
  - Social Club of Wilton, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 907b)
  - Sterling Store, 1754-1799; Includes a list of store patrons. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 909b)
  - Town of Wilton - Act of Incorporation and Bounds Committee report, 1802; See also Town Records, in Register. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 959)
  - Town of Wilton - Animal pound records, 1854 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 960)
  - Town of Wilton - Boundary line, 1710 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1288)
  - Town of Wilton - Bridges - Assembly report and toll rates, 1798 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 190)
  - Town of Wilton - Catalog of scholars and parents, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 970)
  - Town of Wilton - Census records for Wilton, 1728-1810; For the years 1728, 1756, 1774, 1782, and 1810. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 240)
  - Town of Wilton - Court cases heard by Justices of the Peace, 1796-1829; Cases are from 1796, 1813, 1822-23, 1824-26, 1828, and 1829 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 971, 972)
  - Town of Wilton - Death certificates, 1886-1891 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 965)
  - Town of Wilton - Deed to Norwalk, 1640; This is a copy. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 294)
  - Town of Wilton - Distribution of land, 1738-1739 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1290)
  - Town of Wilton - Distribution of money, 1859 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 975)
  - Town of Wilton - Election results, 1892 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 989)
  - Town of Wilton - Expenses, 1807-1810 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 990, 1043)
  - Town of Wilton - Fences, 1829 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 995)
  - Town of Wilton - Government, electors, State Assembly representatives, town meeting notices, 1802-1863 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1015)
  - Town of Wilton - Land deed for Cannon school, 1873; This is a copy. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 980)
  - Town of Wilton - Petition - Danbury Turnpike, 1795-1805; See also WHI, Town Records, Roads. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 780d)
  - Town of Wilton - Petition - Establishing Town of Wilton, 1801 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1033)
  - Town of Wilton - Petition - New Canaan highway, 1819-1823 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1037)
  - Town of Wilton - Poorhouse - Bye-laws, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1026)
  - Town of Wilton - Poorhouse - Rules and bye-laws, 1810-1845 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1025)
  - Town of Wilton - Post Office - Correspondence, undated; See also MC 7-5, 7-6, and 7-7. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 753, 754, 755)
  - Town of Wilton - Post Office - Financial records, 1832-1897 (Box Cabinet: 24, Folder MC 7-5)
  - Town of Wilton - Post Office - Mail account, 1862-1864; Includes an account of mails received at the Post Office at Wilton, County of Fairfield, State of Connecticut. (Box Cabinet: 24, Folder MC 7-1)
  - Town of Wilton - Post Office - Records, undated; See also MC 7-8. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 756)
  - Town of Wilton - Records of perambulation, 1796-1825 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1030)
  - Town of Wilton - Records of the treasurer, 1859; Includes receipts. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1045)
  - Town of Wilton - Roads, 1815-1857 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1035)
  - Town of Wilton - School bonds, 1949 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1038)
  - Town of Wilton - Selectmen's reports, 1805-1955; Reports are for 1805, 1810, 1814, 1815, 1821, 1822, 1829, 1871, 1931, and 1955. (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1000, 1005, 1010)
  - Town of Wilton - Tax collectors and tax payers, 1770-1875 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1040)
  - Town of Wilton - Tax collectors’ records of arrest warrants, unpaid taxes, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1041)
  - Town of Wilton - Tax list of ratable estate, 1815 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1042a)
  - Town of Wilton - Tax rebates and relief, 1776-1778 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1042b)
  - Town of Wilton - Town meeting notices, 1867-1910 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 985)
  - Town of Wilton - Town of Wilton v. Paulson, 1905 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1020)
  - Town of Wilton - Westport Water Company, 1890 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1046)
  - Treaty of Fort Stanwix, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1048a)
  - War - 1812 - Regimental orders (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1164)
  - War - Civil - Correspondence and military records, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1155)
  - War - Revolutionary - Correspondence and military records, 1778-1779 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1158)
  - War - Revolutionary - Danbury raid, undated (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1160)
  - War - Revolutionary - List of Tories, 1781 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1163)
  - War - Revolutionary - Losses and damages, 1778 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1162)
  - Westport Circuit- Subscriptions, 1837-1838 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1180)
  - Wilton Temperance Society, 1829-1833 (Box Cabinet: 7, Folder 1295)